Vikas Sharma

SDE III at Walmart

vks.sharmavikas96@gmail.com

9582296350

linkedin.com/in/vikassharmag6 in

github.com/vikassharmag6 😱

stackoverflow.com/users/10453249/vikas-sharma

WORK EXPERIENCE

SDE III

Walmart Global Tech India

09/2021 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

Altran

09/2020 - Present

Software Engineer

MothersonSumi Infotech & Design

07/2017 - 09/2020

PROJECTS

Honeywell Connect Mobile 3

- App allows you to connect and configure the thermostat device.
- Integrated the thermostat sensors module in the app.

Samsung eStore

- A multilingual eCommerce react native app which uses keycloak for authentication and integrated microservices that follow a BFF design pattern.
- Used Redux toolkit, react-navigationV5, axios, keycloak, geolocation, localization, formik forms.

Factory Forms

- A hybrid app developed with react native which enables even nonprogrammers to effectively create wide range of mobile apps based on different business requirements.
- Core functionality of the app includes form generation and validation from JSON schema.

HRIS1 7

- HRIS1 app provides the most convenient way to mark office attendance by using facial biometrics and geofencing technology.
- This app also include contact tracing which uses BLE in android and shows people in close contact with covid19 infected person.

Enstructor

- An application developed for Vuzix M300 smart glass which enables hands-free process learning and guidance for workers in manufacturing plant. Made deliverables both for wearable glass and android application. [Android + Kotlin]

Connect1 🗹

- Connect1 is a mobile-based console that provides a platform to access application(s) being used in the Samvardhana Motherson Group (SMG). Implemented google recommended MVVM architecture component e.t.c. [Android + Java]

Enlightening Quotes 🗹

- A hybrid app developed with xamarin framework which provides daily new quotes using xamarin forms.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Technology (CSE) - 78% Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

04/2013 - 03/2017 New Delhi

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Seekho Learn in a minute. Remember forever 🗹

Seekho app developed with react native is India's first short learning app made for learners enabling them to learn almost anything in only a minute.

Let's Hear It 🖸

Implemented sound touch library in android using Android NDK and MVVM architecture.

Ebook for E-Advertisement **Technology** **

It is an online business advertisement directory to facilitate the interaction among the business community.

File Tracking 🗹

An android application which tracks files in and out time from various department and know the current status for file.

LuckyWorld 🗹

Developed an android and iOS phishing app which collects user data and a Web App to show users message, call logs, device details and more.

TaskAssistent

A smart watch application used to assign a daily task from server.

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Professional Languages - Java, JavaScript, Kotlin, C#

Tools and Technologies - React Native, Android, Xamarin. AR and VR

Databases - Room, SQLite, Realm

IDE worked on - Android Studio, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Xcode, Unity

Repositories - GIT, Team Foundation Server